

engribrahimghouri@gmail.com

Skype: ibrahim82.ghouri

LinkedIn:pk.linkedin.com/pub/ibrahim-ghouri/41/a47/2b4/



# **Muhammad Ibrahim Khan Ghouri**

### Objective

Over Eight years of dynamic experience in different areas of IT Services desk and IT Operations Involved in monitoring Configuration, installation and troubleshooting Systems problems in challenging environment and wanted to do work where I can utilize my skills and creatively involved with system that effectively contributes to the growth of organization.

#### Experience

#### 4th July 2022 - Present

#### Hamdard Pakistan.

**Deputy Manager - SAP BASIS** 

- SUSE Linux Configuration perspective SAP HANA Packages
- Daily Monitoring SAP Landscape and HANA Database size
- SAP S4 HANA system (DEV-QAS-PRD) installation and post installation
- Database management including database backup and restore, database performance monitor, and analyzing database activity through HANASTUDIO
- Installation of SAP Fiori and Configuration (Front end support)
- FIORI Application and O-Data services activation and configuration
- Client administration including client creation, client copy (Local and remote copy) and delete clients
- Installation and troubleshooting of SAP S4 HANA IDES server
- SAP spool system administration and printer's configuration
- SAP router Installation and configuration. SAP Router License renewal
- Role administration including create / modify roles as per matrix
- Creation of FIORI Roles, Groups, catalog and Profile Generator
- Create and maintain User Reset SAP passwords, set up user IDs and initial passwords
- Reporting to top-level management about Service status (Daily, weekly, monthly reports)

## June 2015 - 30th June 2022

## Tapal Tea (Pvt.) Ltd.

**Information Services Officer - Support SAP Basis** 

- Ensure User access & authorization related tickets are managed properly and on time closure.
- Manage Databases (IBM DB2 & SAP S/4HANA) & monitor file sets, performance optimization and logs management.
- Conduct Transport process in SAP Systems, transfer changes required in system to Quality and Production Instance.
- Support & Executes updates and upgrades in SAP Landscape (SPAM, Kernel, other patches)
- Maintain SAP backups and ensure backup run on schedule and maintain retention.
- Coordinate with auditors for conducting audit activities and provide supporting documents.
- Support System, Network and DR Team while perform disaster recovery drill.
- Maintain confidentiality and integrity of data stored on company compute systems through effective access control.
- Installing, configuring and administering different Servers & workstations (windows Server 2003 / 2008,2012 WSUS)
- Provide support for local and remote users nationwide on all live systems as per agreed KPI and SLA
- Deployment and disposal of hardware and ensure to follow asset inventory movement processes.
- Installation, Configuration, support and maintenance of operating systems LUW

- To coordinate with different vendors for corrective/preventive maintenance of IS equipment.
- Secure all the systems from internal and external attacks by monitoring user activities and report all breaches/abuse.
- Support to others in all initiatives taken by the IS department for improvement.

### May 2014 - June 2015

#### Pfizer Pharma

Help Desk Support Engineer on IOP Pay roll

- Receive and record technical and/or application support calls from end users.
- Provide investigation, diagnosis, resolution and recovery for hardware/software problems. When unable to resolve, escalate to second or third level in accordance with Help Desk escalation processes.
- Maintain overall ownership of user's issue & service ensuring that they receive resolution within a reasonable timeframe.
- Provide initial assessment of urgency and business impact on all support calls.
- Manage service requests, software installations, new computer setups, upgrades, etc.
- Provide enhancement request feedback to IT regarding technology environment and customer needs through the defined processes
- Resolved customer issues on daily basis and close tickets on HP Service Desk and forward tickets to relevant departments.
- Support the following technologies: Microsoft Office 2007 products Outlook, Word, Excel, Access, Internet Explorer, Windows XP, desktops, laptops, printers, networked copiers, NIC's, basic LAN/WAN connectivity and others as assigned.
- Ability to work independently and in a team environment

### ProjectsRenewonDemand-Windows8deployment(July2014-)

Works with Pfizer Regional RoD Project Managers to develop project scope of work documents and project plans that include an analysis of benefit, cost, work schedule and any related risks. Assigns, schedules, trains, reviews, and monitors project work to ensure that progress is within expected guidelines and is completed on time and within budget. Mentors and provides expertise to other project team members. Administers changes to ensure alignment of scope, schedule, resources, and quality and customer expectations is maintained. Works with appropriate customers to identify the roles of project team members, project reporting structures and frequency of interaction and any training requirements that may be needed for team members. Identifies, tracks, monitors and communicates project-related is sues, scope changes, var iances and contingencies that may arise during the implementation of IT projects.

Maintains effective communication and working relationships with customers and project team members. Ensures that the technical approach to be used on a given project is soundly considered, and manages the system development process. Attend project team meetings

### Nov 2013 - April 2014

## UNITED MARINE AGENCIES (Pvt.) Ltd.

Resident Engineer on IOP Pay roll

- Provided IT support of hardware (laptops, desktops, printers etc.) and office applications (windows XP/Vista, win7, win8, etc)
- Installation and configuration of client OS and office applications
- Managed inventory of IT infrastructure (laptops, desktops, printers etc.).
- Setting up user accounts, permissions and passwords.
- Overseeing security of all systems, especially the internet.
- Installing antivirus protection.
- Fixing network faults Analyzing, Identifying and troubleshooting software/hardware problems in a timely manner; resolves routine problems.
- Day to day admin and monitoring of network use.
- IT support team management and providing Level 3 support to users on site.
- Planning future improvements.

## May 2010 - NOV 2012

## MAB GROUP

**IT Support Network Engineer** 

- Involve in support of system administrator in deployment of domain and workgroup policy.
- Configuration/management/monitoring all the networking equipment (Routers, Switches, DSL Modems)
- Install Security Updates, Service Packs and any other OS hotfixes
- Providing high availability of team members.
- Providing fully support in server support task.

- Remote PC Desktop Solutions
- Windows Deployment, Desktop Support
- Troubleshooting/Problem Solving

### **Education**

#### Qualifications

• Sir Syed University of Engineering (Computer Engineering 2006-2010)

Intermediate (Pre-Engineering) (Govt: HidayatUllah College Hyderabad 2004-2005)

Matric (Science) (Al Hira Public school 2002-2003)

### Certifications

## SAP ID: P2002371493

• SAP Certified Technology Associate - System Administration (SAP HANA as a Database) with SAP NetWeaver 7.5)

# Trainings

ITIL Training
 Red Hat Linux (RHCE)
 Business Beam (Pvt.) Ltd
 Synergy Computers (Pvt.) Ltd.

MCSA 2012 - 3D Educators

### **Personal Information**

Father's Name: Abdul Wahid Khan Ghouri (Late)

Date of Birth: 18-Nov-1987
Marital Status: Married

NIC 41308-7623357-3

Address: House# B/30A Alamgir Society Moinabad Malir near Hazrat Shah Jahangir School Karachi.